Guide to the Stanford Oral History Project Interviews SC1017
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Stanford Oral History Project, Series 1
  - Whitaker, Virgil, 1982 May; 145_146; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
    Shakespearean scholar, head of Stanford's English Department (1951-1963) and Dean of the Graduate Division (1964-1968), Professor Whitaker was also the originator and director of the Summer Festival of Arts, and was active in American Indian affairs.
    Interview by Eleanor Bark, Marion Hall and Harvey Hall, transcribed and bound, 47 pages.
    - Transcript (Box 9)
  - Wiggins, Ira, 1980 Apr; 147_148; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
    Professor of Botany at Stanford since 1929. Director of the Natural History Museum and the Dudley Herbarium, (1940-1964). Following his graduation from Occidental College in 1923, he received his A.M. (1925) and Ph.D. (1930) from Stanford.
    Interview by Sara Timby and John Rawlings; transcribed and bound, 57 pages
    - Transcript (Box 9)
  - Wilbur, Dwight Locke, 1981 May; 149_153; 5 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
    Wilbur joined the clinical faculty of the Stanford Medical School in 1937 (Emeritus, 1968-) and became chief of medical services at French Hospital. Dr. Wilbur received his A.B. in Zoology from Stanford (1923) and M.D. from the University of Pennsylvania (1926). The second son of Stanford President Ray Lyman Wilbur, Dr. Wilbur was very active in medical and community affairs. He married Ruth Esther Jordan (Class of 1927) in 1928.
  - Wilbur, Mary Sloan, 1980 Jun 23-24; 154_155; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
    Active in community affairs, including the presidency of the Stanford Hospital Medical Auxiliary, Mrs. Wilbur came to Stanford from Arizona in 1918. Here she met and eventually married Blake Colburn Wilbur (Class of 1922), the eldest son of Stanford President Ray Lyman Wilbur and later one of the founding physicians of the Palo Alto Clinic. Mary earned in BA (Zoology) in 1922.
    Interview by Marion Hall and Ann Chase
  - Yalom, Marilyn, 1987 Jul 16; 156_157; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
    Deputy Director of the Institute for Research on Women and Gender and lecturer in Modern Thought and Literature, Marilyn Yalom was at Stanford from 1976-1987. Interview by Judy Adams
  - Abramovitz, Carrie (Box 14)
  - Almond, Dorothea (Box 14)
  - Alway, Robert (Box 14)
  - Anderson, Reid (Box 14)
  - Angell, Thomas (Box 14)
  - Ashley, Celeste (Box 14)
  - Bacon, Harold (Box 15)
  - Bacon, Rosamund (Box 15)
  - Baer, Carolyn/CCIS (Box 15)
  - Bailey, Thomas A. (Box 15)
  - Barclay, Thomas S. (Box 15)
  - Bark, Eleanor (Box 15)
  - Beard, Rodney (Box 15)
  - Berry, Chester (Box 16)
  - Blake, Marilyn Gillingham, Jane (Box 16)
  - Bliss, James (Box 16)
  - Bloch, Felix (Box 16)
  - Bowes, Ruth Garland (Box 16)
  - Boyd, Harold (Box 16)
  - Brandin, Alf (Box 16)
  - Buchanan, Bruce (Box 16)
  - Buma, Maurine (Box 17)
  - Butler, Lucy (Box 17)
  - Carley, Lucille (Box 17)
  - Ceideberg, Holly (Box 17)
  - Chan, Shau Wing (Box 17)
  - Chandler, Loren (Box 17)
  - Chuck, Frank (Box 17)
  - Clark, Esther (Box 17)
  - Clebsch, Betsy (Box 17)
  - Colby, Edward (Box 17)
  - Craig, Phyllis (Box 17)
  - Crosten, William Loren (Box 17)
  - Davis, Paul Herbert (Box 18)
  - Deal, Bruce E. (Box 18)
  - Denhard, Alice (Box 18)
  - Dodds, John Wendell (Box 19)
  - Drell, Sydney (Box 19)
  - Edgar, Jean (Box 19)
  - Englebart, Doug (Box 20)
  - Eurich, Alvin C. (Box 21)
  - Farnsworth, Paul (Box 21)
  - Fischel, Eleanor Skarin, Miriam (Box 21)
  - Freeman, Szebekski (Sibby) (Box 21)
  - Gardner, John (Box 21)
  - Geballe, Theodore (Box 21)
  - Gibson, Helen (Box 21)
  - Ginzton, Edward (Box 21)
  - Glover, Frederic O. (Box 21)
  - Goheen, John (Box 22)
  - Green Cecil (Box 22)
  - Guthrie, Luell (Box 22)
  - Hall, Harvey (Box 22)
  - Hall, Marion Dwight, Herbert (Box 22)
  - Hanna, Paul (Box 22)
  - Hansen, Ralph (Box 22)
  - Harder, Virginia Crowell, Peggy McCue (Box 23)
  - Hargadon, Fred (Box 23)
  - Harman, John and Jean (Box 23)
  - Harwood, Lee (Box 23)
  - Hastorf, Barbara (Box 23)
  - Hawes, Josephine (Box 23)
  - Hewlett, Bill (Box 23)
  - Hofstadter, Robert (Box 23)
  - Hoover, William G. (Box 23)
  - Howard, Mildred D. Wallingford, J. (Box 23)
  - Jacobson, David S. (Box 24)
  - Jahns, Richard (Box 24)
  - Jessup, Bruce (Box 24)
  - Johnson, Melba Beard (Box 24)
  - Johnson, Olivia (Box 24)
  - Jones, Henry (on R.R. Newell) (Box 24)
  - Jordan, Payton (Box 24)
  - Kaplan, Leah (Box 24)
  - Keen, Myra (Box 25)
  - Kendrick, Betty Roth (Box 25)
  - Keohane, Nannerl (Box 25)
  - Kirkpatrick, Paul (Box 25)
  - Krauskopf, Konrad (Box 25)
  - Kriss, Joseph (Box 25)
  - Leu, Anna Jagels (Box 25)
  - Levison, Robert Mark (Box 26)
  - Lewis, Janet (Box 26)
  - Linvill, John (Box 26)
  - Lowenstein, Gerald (Box 26)
  - Lyman, Elizabeth (Jing) (Box 26)
  - Manson, Clara (Box 27)
  - Mendelowitz, Daniel (Box 27)
  - Mitchell, Sydney (Box 27)
  - Murphy, Michael (Box 27)
  - Newell, Allen (on R.R. Newell) (Box 27)
  - Newell, Jeanette (on R.R. Newell) (Box 27)
  - Newell, Robert R. (Box 27)
  - Nunan, Craig (Box 27)
  - Packard, Martin (Box 28)
  - Panofsky, Wolfgang (Box 28)
  - Purdy, Ann Peril (Box 28)
  - Rhinelander, Phil (Box 28)
  - Richards, Victor (Box 28)
  - Richter, Burton (Box 28)
  - Ricker, Christine (Box 28)
  - Robinson, Edgar E. (Box 28)
  - Rosenzweig, Robert M. (Box 28)
  - Schawlow, Arthur (Box 29)
  - Schofield, Mary (Box 29)
  - Sears, Robert R. (Glover interviews) (Box 29)
  - Sears, Robert R. (Box 29)
  - Sears, Robert R. (Cravens interviews) (Box 30)
  - Slaven, Helen Adell (Box 31)
  - Snitjer, Kate (Box 31)
  - Snyder, Rixford K. (Box 31)
  - Sterling, Wallace (Box 31)
  - Sterling, Wallace (group reminiscence) (Box 31)
  - Stolz, Lois Meek (Box 31)
  - Swank, Raynard C. (Box 31)
  - Terman, Frederick Emmons (Box 32)
  - Vickers, Joseph W. (Box 32)
  - Whitaker, Virgil K. (Box 32)
  - Wiggins, Ira Loren (Box 33)
  - Wilbur, Dwight L. (Box 33)
  - Wilbur, Mary Sloan (Box 33)
  - Yalom, Marilyn (Box 33)
- Aurora Interviews, Series 2 (Box 4)
  - Applewhite, Liat, 1981 May 12; 158; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
    General note
    Interview by Sally Thomas and Stephanie Poggi
  - Bancroft, Kim and Jensen, Margaret, 1981 Apr 23; 159_160; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Brown, Phyllis, 1981 May; 161; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
    Interview by Sally Thomas and Stephanie Poggi.
    Brown was a founder and early participant in Aurora feminist student newspaper at Stanford.
    - Transcript
  - Mercer, Michelle, 1981 May 12; 163; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Merriman, Sue, 1981 May; 164; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Smith, Stephanie and Gonzales, Leenda, 1981 May 12, 1985 May 6; 165, 123; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Torf, Adrienne, 1981 May 12, 1985 Jun 4; 166; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
- Community Committee on International Students (CCIS), Series 3 (Box 4)
  - Baer, Carolyn, 1984 Dec 19; 167; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
    Interview by Lee Harwood and Virginia Spears; transcribed, 27 pages
    - Transcript (Box 9)
  - Botsford, Margaret, 1985 May 22; 168; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
    Interview by Carolyn Grundt; transcribed, 23 pages
    - Transcript (Box 9)
  - Bretall, Norah, 1987 Mar 30; 169; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Cline, Laura, 1987 Feb 2; 170; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Dutton, Dorothea, 1987 Mar 31; 171; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Gibson, Helen, 1986 Mar 10; 172; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
    Interview by Roka Haswell.
    Interview includes descriptions of hosted students and of students who worked for board and room; mostly Chinese students. Employment vs. friendship and hosting, keeping boundaries.
  - Goff, Harry and Goff, Kay, 1987 Mar 30; 173; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
    Descriptions of students the Goffs hosted and have kept in touch with; how Bechtel center was acquired
    - Transcript (Box 9)
  - Grundt, Carolyn Stipe, 1984 Jul 7; 174; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
    Interview by Roka Haswell; 23 minutes
  - Harwood, Lee, 1984 Aug 6; 175; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    Interview by Virginia Spears and Gertrude Williams; 36 minutes
  - Haswell, Roka, 1984 Jul 6; 176; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    Interview by Annette Mellott; 55 minutes
  - Johnston, Beatrice and Silber, Bernice, 1986 Mar 10; 177; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    Interview by Lee Harwood and Bernice Silber; 27 minutes
  - Kershaw, Henrietta, 1985 Apr 9; 178; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    Interview by Roka Haswell; 43 minutes
  - Keyes, Pat, 1984 Sep 27; 179; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    Interview by Virginia Spears and Gertrude Williams; 38 minutes
  - Krebs, Ruby, 1986 Mar 18; 180; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    Interview by Carolyn Stipe; 47 minutes
  - Lane, Joane, 1987 Mar 18; 181; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Mellott, Annette, 182; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    Interview by Carolyn Grundt, July 6, 1984; 30 minutes
  - Millar, Kay, 1986 Jul 22; 183; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    Interview by Gertrude Williams and Virginia Spears; 40 minutes
    - Transcript (Box 9)
  - Norman, Ruth, 1987 Mar 30; 184; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Page, Virginia, 1987 Apr 15; 185; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    Interview covers early organizational structure and participants of CCIS; location(s) of the CCIS program on campus; Homestay Program and permanent housing; personal connections to Japanese students; students in School of Earth Sciences; students who return to their home countries vs. students who stay in the US; rewards of participating in the program.
  - Proctor, Elizabeth, 1986 Jun 10; 186; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    Interview by Carolyn Stipe; 50 minutes
  - Qualls, Katherine, 1985 Sep 18; 188; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Roesler, Fran, 187; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Rusmore, Jean, 1986 Jun 2; 189; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    Interview by Lee Harwood and Bernice Silber; 35 minutes
  - Spaeth, Sheila, 1985 Apr 26; 191; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    Interview by Virginia Spears and Gertrude Williams; 30 minutes.
    Spaeth discusses the early organizational structure and participants of CCIS
    - Transcript (Box 9)
  - Spears, Virginia, 1984 Jul 16; 192; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    Interview by Gertrude Williams and Lee Harwood; 45 minutes.
    Interview includes descriptions of students the Spears hosted and have kept in touch with; students from India and Japan featured.
  - Warnlof, Mary Ann, 1984 Nov 28; 193; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    Interview by Carolyn Grundt; 38 minutes
  - Wells, Alison, 1986 Jul 21; 194; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Williams, Gertrude, 1984 Jul 11; 195; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    - Transcript (Box 9)
  - Wright, Mabel, 196; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    Interview by Roka Haswell
- Laser History Project Interviews, Series 4 (Box 5)
  - Dwight, Herbert McGilvray, 1984 Jan 18; 54; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
    By Joan BrombergAt Spectra-Physics, San Jose, California
    See Hall, Marion Dwight.
  - Goldsborough, John, 198; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    Laser specialist. Received his B.S. from Lehigh University in 1956, and Ph.D. in Physics from Stanford University in 1961. Research staff member, 1960-1966, Director of Research, 1966-1968, and Senior Project Engineer, 1968-1974 at International Business Machines Corporation; Engineering Department Manager, Spectra-Physics, Inc. Has conducted research on Magnetic Resonance, photo conductivity, and low temperature physics.
    Interview focuses on his research at Spectra-Physics.
  - Hänsch, Theodor, 199; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    Winner of 2005 Nobel Prize in Physics, along with John L. Hall, for their contributions to the development of laser-based precision spectroscopy, including the optical frequency comb technique. A native of West Germany, and specialist in lasers and physics. Received his M.S. (1966) and Ph.D. (1969) in physics from the University of Heidelberg. Assistant professor of physics, University of Heidelberg, 1969-1970, NATO fellow 1970-1972, and associate professor, 1972-1975. Concurrent position as Sloan Foundation Fellow, 1973-1975. Professor of Physics, Stanford University, 1975-1986. Alexander Von Humboldt Sr. U.S. Scientist Fellow, 1978-79. Research accomplishments in spectroscopy and quantum electronics; developed powerful monochromatic pulsed dye lasers; high resolution nonlinear spectroscopy of atoms and molecules.
    Interview covers: laser research at the University of Heidelberg, 1965-1970. Thesis research. Collaboration on a commercial laser. Hansch's laboratory style. Frustrations of doing spectroscopy with the early, non-tunable lasers. Laser research at Stanford University, 1970-circa 1973. Comparison of resources at Heidelberg and Stanford. The high resolution, tunable laser of 1971 and the research program it engendered.
    - Transcript (Box 9)
  - Hobart, J., 200_201; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    Oral history interview covers: Hobart's background at the University of Michigan and with Trion Instruments Company; his management of accessory-product development at Spectra-Physics; Coherent Radiation, Inc., and the Coherent Carbon Dioxide laser; Spectra-Physics--Coherent rivalry; Coherent's service and customer training policies; sources of capital; developing a commercial argon-ion laser; the start of profitability for Coherent in 1969.
  - Rempel, Robert, 202; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    Oral history interview covers the founding of Spectra-Physics; Rempel's reasons for choosing to be an entrepreneur; attitudes toward patenting; the collaboration with Perkin-Elmer; Role of John Atwood; Spectra-Physics' advertising approach; acquisitions; pricing policies; steps toward achieving high quality products; the step camera; the geodolite.
    B.A. Pomona College (1948); M.S. Stanford University (1950); Ph.D. in Physics (1956). Varian Associates consult. 1954-1956, resident physicist, 1956-1961. President Spectra-Physics, Inc., 1961-1970, and Chromatix, Inc., 1970-1980.
  - Ruddock, K., 203; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    Interview covers: Designing magnetometers at Varian; early non-laser ''bread and butter" development projects for Spectra-Physics; laser rangefinders for airborne commercial applications. Also covers the Spectra-Physics geodolite and its applications to geologic surveys, mapping of Artic ice, aircraft and missile tracking, and ocean wave heights.
  - Schawlow, Arthur B., 204_205; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    Interview covers: Boyhood in Ontario, Canada. High school and college education, graduate work at the University of Toronto. Post-doctoral research in microwave spectroscopy at Columbia University with Charles Townes. Influence of peers and professors. Bell Labs, research in superconductivity and in lasers. Development in communication ability of autistic son. Move of Stanford. Connections with "Silicon Valley" industry.
    Physicist, specializing in lasers. Winner of 1981 Nobel Prize in Physics for his contributions to laser spectroscopy. Professor of physics, Stanford University, 1961-1996.
  - Siegman, A.E., 1931-2011, 206; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    Tony Siegman was born November 23, 1931, and raised in rural Michigan. He received the AB degree summa cum laude after three years as a National Merit Scholar at Harvard, where he played the clarinet in the Harvard Marching Band. After two years on a cooperative plan with the Hughes Research Labs in Culver City, leading to an MS degree in Applied Physics from UCLA in 1954, he followed his former Hughes supervisor, Dr. Dean A. Watkins, to Stanford as a research assistant. He was appointed to the Stanford faculty on an acting basis in 1956 and received the PhD degree in Electrical Engineering in 1957 with a dissertation on microwave noise in electron beams and traveling-wave tubes. Shortly thereafter he switched to work on microwave masers and parametric devices, which, after 1960, evolved into a research and teaching career in lasers and optics. He was promoted to full professor at Stanford in 1964 and retired from his Stanford position as the Burton J. and Ann M. McMurtry Professor of Engineering in November 1998. Following his formal retirement, he continued to lecture, consult, and publish in his field, including work on gain-guided optical fibers and fiber lasers. In 2010 he made a round-the-world trip on behalf of LaserFest, celebrating 50 years of laser innovation. From 1999 through 2011 he spent winters at north Tahoe, cross-country skiing daily with his wife and dogs. A campus resident, he was a founding officer of the Stanford Campus Residential Leaseholders, Inc., and also served on the boards of the Stanford Historical Society and the Stanford Emeriti Council. His other interests included antique scientific instruments, opera, sailing, and snorkelling. During his Stanford career he supervised some 40 PhD dissertations and published numerous scientific articles and three textbooks: Microwave Solid-State Masers (McGraw-Hill, 1964), An Introduction to Lasers and Masers (McGraw-Hill, 1972), and Lasers (University Science Books, 1986). Lasers, at 1,283 pages, became the standard reference in the field. He was regarded by many as a true patriarch, since one of his Ph.D. students, Stephen E. Harris, continued on to his own prominence on the Stanford faculty and in turn supervised the Ph.D. of (now) Stanford professor Robert L. Byer. Byer in turn supervised the Ph.D. of (now) professor Martin M. Fejer, several of whose students have gone on to notable careers and have mentored students of their own, making four generations of academic "offspring" in Quantum Electronics and other fields. Burton J. McMurtry, another of Tony's early Ph.D. students, served most recently as president of Stanford's Board of Trustees. Tony was Director of the Ginzton Laboratory from 1978 to 1983 and again in 1998-99, and served on numerous academic committees and as a member of the Stanford Faculty Senate and its Steering Committee. He spent sabbaticals as Visiting Professor of Applied Physics at Harvard in 1965, Guggenheim Fellow at the IBM Research Labs in Zurich in 1969-70, and Humboldt Senior Scientist at the Max Planck Institute for Quantum Optics in Garching, Germany, in 1984-85. Tony was an active participant in the historic first Quantum Electronics symposium at Shawanga Lodge in 1959, which marked the start of serious research into lasers. Thereafter, he began to move his research from microwaves and masers to optics and lasers. Early in his career he was Program Chair for the 1966 International Quantum Electronics Conference and Conference Chair for the 1968 IQEC, and later served as co-director of laser schools in South Korea and Taiwan. He was a member of the U.S. Air Force Scientific Advisory Board during 1974-80 and served on advisory groups for NBS, NIST, NSF, and other government agencies. He received a number of awards from major professional societies, held several patents in his field, and was elected to the National Academy of Engineering in 1973 and the National Academy of Sciences in 1988. In 1996 he was elected as Vice-President of the Optical Society of America, serving as President of the OSA during 1999. He married the former Virginia (Jeannie) Howard in 1974. He is survived by his wife Jeannie, his children by a previous marriage: Anne Lorraine (Jessica), Winn, and Patrick; by his stepdaughter Elaine Lissner; and his two grandchildren.
    Oral history interview traces his path to Stanford and his career as a faculty member, focusing on Siegman's education from 1949 to 1957 as an undergraduate at Harvard, a Hughes Aircraft Company work-study fellow at the University of California in Los Angeles, and a Ph.D. candidate at Stanford University.
    - Transcript (Box 9)
- Stanford Nurse Alumnae Interviews, Series 5 (Box 5)
  - Blake, Marilyn and Gillingham, Jane, 1988 Apr 30; 207; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    - Transcript (Box 9)
  - Carley, Lucille O., 208; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    - Transcript (Box 9)
  - Crowell, Peggy and Harder, Virginia Bennett, 1980 Apr 29; 209_210; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    - Transcript (Box 9)
  - Denhard, Alice, 1988 Mar 23; 211; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    - Transcript (Box 9)
  - Edgar, Jean, 1988 Apr 30; 212; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    - Transcript (Box 9)
  - Fischel, Eleanor and Skarin, Miriam, 1988 Jun 14; 213; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    - Transcript (Box 9)
  - Geddo, Frances, Hutting, Ruth, Mori, Masae, 306; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 11)
  - Hawes, Josephine, 1985 Aug 9; 214; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    - Transcript (Box 9)
  - Howard, Mildred Dye and Wallingford, Janice Lee, 1988 Apr 30; 215; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    - Transcript (Box 9)
  - Johnson, Melba Beard, 1988 Apr 30; 216; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
    1934 grad of Stanford school of nursing; describes schooling and subsequent career.
    - Transcript
  - Ringressy, Grace, 1988 Apr 13; 274; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 7)
  - Slaven, Helen Adell, 1988 May; 217; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Smith, Edythe, 1986; 305; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 11)
- Silicon Valley Project Interviews, Series 6 (Box 5)
  - Anderson, Reid, 1987 May; 218_221; 4 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
    Physics, engineering. Magnetic storage devices and electronics. Bell Labs, Anderson-Jacobson, Inc., Verbatim.
    Interview by Henry Lowood; transcribed, 74 pages
    - Transcript (Box 9)
  - Bliss, James, 1987 Jun-Aug; 222_224; 3 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
    Engineering. SRI, Founder of Telesensory Systems.
    Interview by Judy Adams; transcribed, 55 pages
    - Transcript (Box 9)
  - Deal, Bruce E., 1988 Jun-Nov; 225_228, 55_56; 6 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
    Consulting professor of electrical engineering at Stanford; chemist, helped to develop metal oxide semiconductor technology during the early 1960s at Rheem Semiconductor and Fairchild Semiconductor. Interview covers his education, work experience, his relationship with Silicon Valley pioneers, and the contacts between Stanford and Silicon Valley researchers.
    Interview by Henry Lowood
    - Transcript (Box 9)
  - Engelbart, Douglas C., 1986 Dec-1987 Apr; 229_236; 8 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
    Computer Science (SRI). Inventor of the "Mouse" and design of the computer work station concept and software.
    Interview by Judy Adams and Henry Lowood; transcribed, 184 pages
    - Transcript (Box 9)
  - Ginzton, Edward, 1987 Aug-1988 Mar; 237_242, 103; 7 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
    Professor of Applied Physics and Electrical Engineering, 1946-1968. Helped develop Klystron tube with Professor William Hansen and the Varian brothers; developed microwave tubes. Director, Stanford Microwave Laboratories (1949-1959), Project M (SLAC) (1957-1960). President (1964-1968), Chairman of the Board (1959-1984), Varian Associates.
    Interview by Joel Shurkin, Henry Lowood and Bruce Hevly
    - Transcript (Box 9)
  - Hewlett, William, 1989 Oct 26; 115_116; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
    Engineer and the co-founder, with David Packard, of the Hewlett-Packard Company (HP). Hewlett received his Bachelor's degree from Stanford University in 1934, an MS degree in electrical engineering from MIT in 1936, and the degree of Electrical Engineer from Stanford in 1939. Hewlett attended classes taught by Fred Terman at Stanford and became acquainted with David Packard during his undergraduate work at Stanford. He and Packard began discussing forming a company in August 1937, and founded Hewlett-Packard Company as a partnership on January 1, 1939. The company incorporated in 1947 and tendered an initial public offering in 1957. He was President of HP from 1964 to 1977, and served as CEO from 1968 to 1978. He remained chairman of the executive committee until 1983, and then served as vice chairman of the board until 1987.
    - Transcript (Box 8)
  - Linvill, John, 1919-2011, 1987 May 5; 243; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)